# BABALOLA, ALICE OLUWABUKOLA

401A Omofade Crescent, Omole phase 1 Ojodu Berger, Lasgos State. Tel•+2349098905549/ +2348080060046 Email• aliceajakaye@gmail.com

# **SUMMARY**

I am a seasoned program and project manager with competencies to effectively manage time, people and resources as a result I have experience in leadership, management and operations of running an organization with people of like minds. I seek a challenging role where I can utilize the skills, knowledge and experience gathered over the years to achieve the vision and mission of your organization while acquiring new ones.

I have strong communication skills, with capacity to collaborate with all degrees of the executives, a characteristic cooperative person, and keen on ability to interact with all levels of management, a natural team player, and keen on delivering top-notch service with quantifiable outcome.

# **PROFESSIONAL COMPETENCY**

- Creativity with some excellent problem-solving skills.
- Proficient in Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)
- Ability to use GANTT chart to coordinate activities in a timely and budget friendly manner.
- Reporting and Presentation skills
- An attentive listener, always patient to solve customers' enquiry and complaints.
- Resourceful, flexible, and innovative in a demanding work environment
- Profinciency in current project management tools like Jira, Trello etc.
- Deliver tasks with high precision and in detailed manner.
- High level of attention to details.
- Excellent interpersonal skill with strong verbal and written communication skill.
- High level of Organizational skill and Leadership ability, gained through volunteering experience.
- I work effectively in a team with great contributions and commitments.

#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

#### **Ornaments of Grace and Virtue (Non-Governmental Organization)**

2021 - 2022

Post Held: Programme Manager/Operations Officer

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Draw up budget, planning and organizing programs for the organization.
- Develop reports on ongoing programs and submit to management and coordinate daily schedules.
- Teach and facilitate training for girls in secondary schools through mentorship and counseling.
- Hiring and training volunteers and staff for various positions within the organization
- Coordinating activities of volunteers on the field depending on the project being executed.
- Allocate resources and supplies to ensure volunteers complete their responsibilities.
- Support and connect with other NGOs/Attend meetings and programs
- Draw up a work schedule for the week/keep a record of inventories
- Carry out necessary registrations as at when due and dispatching of letters
- Manage and coordinate office operations.

- Participates in designing and development of bursary, scholarship plan, training modules, filing, reporting and documentation.
- Setting up appointments and scheduling meetings

### InsideOjodu Media (Online)

2018 – till Present

Post Held: Reporter/Presenter

### **Responsibilities**:

- Reporting happenings in Ojodu communities and its environment
- Writing, Rewriting, Editing and Publishing new stories on the news site.
- Conducting Personality Interviews and creating Vox pop topics and content for the onlineTv.
- Creating Documentary (research, scripting and voiceover) for the online Tv.

#### **NatnudO Foods (National Youth Service)**

2019 - 2020

**Post Held:** Activation/Marketing Representative Customer Satisfaction Representative

### **Responsibilities**:

- Creating awareness for the brand visibility of the company with outdoor and indoor activation.
- Calling customer on the status of their products such as product delivery, packaging, product ordering or any other related issues with the products.
- Calling the customers on survey for price review and other research.
- Receiving calls from customers on enquiry of product availability, types/specs, location on where the product can be purchased and confirming the status of their products.
- Receiving calls on complaints and observation of product and sales personnel.
- Organizing trainings among the team every week to keep up to date with how to deliver effective customer service.
- Worked with a team to build content for the new website created for customers to order product online.

#### **Lagos State Command (Emergency help line)**

2015

Consol Nigeria Limited

Post Held: Call centre agent

#### **Responsibilities**:

- Handling of distress calls from society.
- Escalate emergency cases through customer relationship management (CRM).

#### **Top Radio & Traffic Radio**

2017-2018

**Post held:** Radio Presenter (On Security 247)

#### **Responsibilities:**

• Co-host on Security 24/7, a Saturday show targeted at teaching children and teenagers on how to be security conscious.

#### **Sofan Estal Industry Ltd (Human hair extension)**

2015 - 2016

Post Held: Account Clark and Operations Officer

#### **Responsibilities**:

- Draw up budget and salary schedule for staff members and casual workers.
- Coordinate daily operations of production in the organization from the factory workers to the store keeper until the goods get to the marketers for delivery.
- Monitor sales and customers in market for satisfactory sales.
- Prepare weekly report of sales, workers performance and attendance.

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE				
Dean Initiative (Project Coordinator)	2021- till date			
<b>Duties:</b> Teaching at School Hygiene Education Training Program				
Coordinating and supervising the distribution of volunteers to var	ious location during			
the campaign on community sensitization of PVC registration and voting				
Coordinate and manage volunteers' activities during the campaign	on community			
sensitization of PVC registration and voting				
African Clean Up Initiative (Volunteer)	2019 – till date			
<b>Duties:</b> Clean up environment and educating the public on the need for recenvironment.	cycling and safe			
Lagos Food Bank Initiative (Volunteer)	2018 - till date			
Duties: Distribution of food stuffs to rural communities in Lagos, last Fric	lay of every month.			
Make A Move Initiative (Founder & Programs coordinator)	2017 - till date			
<b>Duties:</b> Recruiting and managing activities of volunteers				
Coordinating Team Leads across 7 States				
Sourcing for Sponsors and Partners				
Funding Raising				
Project Revamp Africa (Volunteer)	2017 – till date			
<b>Duties:</b> Facilitator and mentor students secondary school				
Helping to sort out some admin works at the office during my free	hours			
TRAINING AND DEVELOPMENT				
Agile project management certification	In View			
Web Development Training	In View			
Diploma in Project Management	2022			
<ul> <li>Certified Coach with Strength Factory Organization</li> </ul>	2022			
<ul> <li>Leadership and Entrepreneurship Development</li> </ul>	2022			
(White Field Foundation)				
<ul> <li>Leadership and Entrepreneurship Development</li> </ul>	2020			
(African ChangeMaker)	2020			
<ul><li>(African ChangeMaker)</li><li>Public Speaking Training</li></ul>	2020			
	2019			

# QUALIFICATIONS AND AWARDS WITH DATE

Qualifications	Awards			
<ul> <li>Public Speaking Certificate</li> </ul>	2020	•	Outstanding Volunteer	2019
<ul> <li>Upper Credit (HND)</li> </ul>	2018	•	Most Supportive Foundation	2019
<ul> <li>Upper Credit( ND)</li> </ul>	2015	•	Best Student in Features Writing (2015)	2018
• IJMB (A' level)	2009	•	Most Intelligent Students	<u>2</u> 017

# **EDUCATION**

NIGERIAN INSTITUTE OF JOURNALISM (NIJ) LAGOS STATE	2016 - 2018				
Higher National Diploma, Broadcast Journalism					
NIGERIAN INSTITUTE OF JOURNALISM (NIJ) LAGOS STATE	2013 - 2015				
National Diploma, Mass Communication					
REFERENCE					

# **Available on Request**